Guide to the Oliver Mayer Papers, ca. 1970-1998
Department of Special Collections
Oliver Mayer Papers,
ca. 1970-1998
Special Collections M0973
Mayer, Oliver.
16.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Purchased, 1998.
Biography
Los Angeles playwright with a Latino background. His mother is Mexican-American, an actress who gave up the theatre for marriage; his late father, Alexander, was a film and television art director. A self-described "punk" in high school, Mayer went on to a highly successful academic career at Cornell, Oxford and Columbia universities. BLADE TO THE HEAT has received the most attention of the some dozen plays he has written. He inherited his passion for boxing from his father and Mexican grandfather and trained in the sport from the ages of 13 to 15.
Scope and Content
Includes manuscripts, corrected typescripts, childhood stories and drawings, correspondence, diaries, business papers and letters, press reviews and coverage, publications, posters, and photographs.
Container List
This is a preliminary box inventory only
- Tears will tell it all [play] 1980s (Box 1)
- Tears (Blade) play (Box 1)
- Blade to the heat [play] 1990s (Box 1)
- Joy of the desolate (Box 1)
- Blade to the heat (Box 2)
- Unfinished plays (Box 3)
- Unfinished work (Box 3)
- Fortune is a woman [play] (Box 4)
- Machiavelli [novel, movie] (Box 4)
- Machiavelli papers (Box 4)
- Awards (Box 5)
- Medals, child's shoes (Box 5)
- Essays/articles 1970-1990 (Box 5)
- Childrens drawings 1970-1980 (Box 6)
- Short stories 1980-1990 (Box 6)
- Poems 1980-1990 (Box 6)
- Joe Louis Blues [play] (Box 7)
- Gog [play] (Box 8)
- Young Valieant [play] (Box 8)
- So much for winning [play] (Box 9)
- Personal letters to Mom 1980-1990 (Box 10)
- The crossing (Box 10)
- Papers 1990-1996 (Box 10)
- Boxing Illustrated [screenplay] (Box 10)
- The road to Los Angeles [play] (Box 11)
- Manifest destiny [screenplay] (Box 11)
- Rock and roll [movie] (Box 11)
- Who's the boss [screenplay] (Box 11)
- La Rabia [play] (Box 11)
- The Chess Machine [play] (Box 11)
- Oxford/Words (Box 11)
- Dramatic monologues (Box 11)
- England/Italy 1985 (Box 11)
- Origin of the Foil [play] (Box 11)
- Words upon words [play] (Box 11)
- Notebook diaries 1980-1998 (Box 12)
- Reviews (Blade mostly) (Box 13)
- Blade papers, letters (Box 13)
- Business papers and letters (Box 14)
- Personal letters (Box 15)
- Papers (assorted) (Box 15)
- Strong as death [play] (Box 16)
- Blade [screenplay] (Box 16)
- George C. Wolfe letter (Box 16)
- Madonna correspondence (Box 16)
- Blade letters/scrapbook (Box 16)
- Blade photos (Box 16)
- Publications (Box 17)
- Press coverage (Box 18)
- High school, junior high school (Box 19)
- Essays (various), Victims' rights, Holyfield essay, Rings (Box 19)
- My heart's in the highlands, Strong as death, So much for winning (Box 19)
- Columbia panel w/ Bill Jones 1997 (Box 19)
- Sevilla [screenplay] (Box 19)
- Ragged time [play] (Box 19)
- (This box sent 2 weeks after rest) (Box 20)
- Young Valiant (Box 20)
- Correspondence (Box 20)
- Heartbreak Soup (Box 20)
- Video of Blade (Box 20)
- Water damaged materials (Box 21)
- Print box: posters, etc. (Box 22)